http://www.thebourne.org.uk/privacy-notice.php

Parish Info Sign Up
HomeLife and WorshipOur ChurchesThe United BeneficeServicesOur FaithOur VisionGet InvolvedPrayersOur TeamThe PCCOur Volunteer Working GroupsHome WorshipChristeningsWeddingsFunerals and ThanksgivingsParish DocumentsSurveyWhat's OnActivities in Our ChurchesYear of MusicNews & EventsBroadsheet Parish Info Sign Up - including NewsletterParish CalendarThe Bourne Magazine OnlineChildren & Young PeopleJunior ChurchChoirsBabes & TotsOur Choirs & MusicAbout the choirsHistory of the ChoirNews & RecitalsChoir ToursJoin our ChoirsVideo about our choirsListen to our musicSt Thomas' OrganSupport our ChoirsGallery Photo Library IndexPhotosSecret Gardens in Lockdown2020 Parish Events2019 - Parish EventsChoir Tour to Venice2018 - Parish Events2017 - Parish EventsParish Pilgrimage November 2016Choir Tour to CologneLife in the choir2016 - Parish EventsChildren and Youth activities2015 Parish EventsChoir at London charity eventChoir Tour to Prague2013-2014 Parish EventsChoir Tour to London and Oxford2012 Parish EventsOur busy centenary year 2010-2011Bourne Parish 100 years agoTour around Brambleton HallTour around St Martin'sTour around St Thomas'CookiesFunction RoomsGivingGiving to support our ParishHow to donateGiving our time and talentsOur Supported Charities
Home > Privacy Notice
DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
The Parochial Church Council (PCC) of The Parish of The Bourne, Farnham
1. Your personal data – what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data.  The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
2. Who are we?
The PCC of The Bourne Parish, Farnham is the data controller (contact details are given in section 9).  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes. The PCC is a registered charity, number 1127825.
3. How do we process your personal data?
The PCC of The Bourne Parish, Farnham complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes: -
To enable us to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public in Farnham as specified in our constitution
To administer membership records and planned giving records and Gift Aid returns
To fundraise and promote the interests of the Parish as a registered charity
To manage our employees and volunteers
To maintain our own accounts and records
To inform you of news, events, activities and services running in the parish and the diocese of Guildford
To share your contact details with the Diocesan office or Charity Commissioners where required (see paragraph 5 below);
To comply with the Church’s Safeguarding Policies where appropriate
The Bourne Parish maintains a secure electronic database, using a third-party provider called “ChurchSuite”, which enables us to function more effectively as a church community and ensure personal data is secure and only accessible to authorised users.  Our ChurchSuite account is hosted in the UK and we have chosen to use it because of the ease of use of their software and their compliance with the GDPR.  ChurchSuite also has a member-facing system called “My ChurchSuite”, which (among other features) enables those on the database to manage their own personal information easily, or opt out at any time.  All personal information stored on our ChurchSuite account is backed up securely each day.  If you would like more information about our use of ChurchSuite please email pcc@thebourne.org.uk . For more information about ChurchSuite generally, see their website www.churchsuite.com
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
We process some data to carry out legal obligations in relation to Gift Aid or under employment law. We also have legal obligations under Canon Law and Church of England rules, including processing data in relation to the Electoral Roll.
Most of our data processing, including contacting you, is carried out as a legitimate interest by a not-for-profit body with a religious aim provided that:-
the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and
there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
For the purposes of this notice members are deemed to include:-
those who are on the electoral roll of the parish
those who worship regularly at one of our churches or halls
those who support the parish financially through regular giving by standing order or via the Parish Giving Scheme
Where your information is used other than in accordance with one of these legal bases, we will first obtain your consent to that use as outlined below:
To obtain your explicit consent to contact you by email or other electronic means so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities, fund-raising and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about diocesan events.
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We will not share your data with third parties outside of the parish without your consent.
We have a legal obligation to notify the Diocese of Guildford of the names and contact details of Office Holders such as Churchwardens, Deanery Synod members, PCC Treasurer, Gift Aid administrator, PCC Secretary as well as sharing personal data for the purposes of obtaining DBS checks. We also are required to notify the Charity Commissioners of the members of the PCC.
6. How long do we keep your personal data1?
We keep data in accordance with the guidance set out in the guide “Keep or Bin: Care of Your Parish Records” which is available from the Church of England website [see footnote for link].
Specifically, we retain electoral roll data while it is still current; gift aid declarations and associated paperwork for up to 6 years after the calendar year to which they relate; and parish registers (baptisms, marriages, funerals) permanently.
7. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data: -
The right to request a copy of your personal data which the PCC of The Bourne Parish, Farnham holds about you;
The right to request that the PCC of The Bourne Parish, Farnham corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the PCC of The Bourne Parish, Farnham to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to object to the processing of personal data, where applicable.
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.
8. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Parish Administrator via theparishoffice@thebourne.org.uk or 01252 715505.
You can contact the Information Commissioners Office on 0303 123 1113 or via email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/ or at the Information Commissioner's Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire. SK9 5AF.
1 Details about retention periods can currently be found in the Record Management Guides located on the Church of England website at: - https://www.churchofengland.org/about-us/structure/churchcommissioners/administration/librariesandarchives/recordsmanagementguides.aspx
Contact us
The Bourne Parish office is based at St Thomas-on-The Bourne
Frensham Road, Farnham Surrey GU9 8HA Tel: 01252 715505
email: theparishoffice@thebourne.org.uk
| Cookies
This church website is powered by Church Edit| Privacy Notice
Registered Charity No 1127825
